- [Instructor] The first step
of training a machine learning
algorithm is loading the training data.
TensorFlow supports different
ways of loading datasets,
depending on how much
data you are dealing with.
The more data that you have,
the more complicated it gets.
The simplest method is
to preload all your data
into memory and pass it to
TensorFlow as a single array.
To do this, you just write
plain Python code to load your data.
There's nothing TensorFlow specific.
The second more complicated
option is to write code
that feeds your training data step-by-step
into TensorFlow as TensorFlow requests it.
This gives you more control
over when the data is loaded
but it requires you to
manage everything yourself.
The third option is to set up
a custom data pipeline in TensorFlow.
This is the best option
when you are working
with enormous datasets
like millions of images.
A data pipeline allows
TensorFlow to manage loading data
into memory itself as it needs it.
Let's take a deeper look at these options.
Preloading all your data into memory
is the most straightforward approach.
You simply read your
data file into an array
and pass that array to TensorFlow.
This approach only works
as long as the data
will fit into your
computer's available memory.
For example, if you
want to train the model
with a 100 gigabytes of financial data,
but your computer only
has 32 gigabytes of RAM,
this approach won't work.
You won't be able to
fit the entire dataset
into memory at once.
When you are loading
your data into memory,
you code it however you
want as long as the data
ends up in a multidimensional array.
You don't need to use any
TensorFlow specific functions.
But you can use all the
helpful Python libraries
that make it easy to work with data.
One of the most popular
libraries is called pandas.
Pandas is great for
loading data from CSV files
and then preprocessing that data
to get it ready for TensorFlow.
Feeding data step-by-step
is a more complicated
version of preloading data.
Instead of preloading the
entire dataset at once,
TensorFlow calls your
customer data loader function
whenever it needs the next chunk of data.
It's up to you to write
the code that loads
and returns that next chunk of data.
This approach gives you more control.
And since you only have
to load one chunk of data
at a time, instead of
preloading the entire dataset,
it's possible to process
very large datasets.
But you have to write all the
data loading code yourself.
The custom data loader function is written
in normal Python code.
You can make it as simple
or as complex as you need.
TensorFlow data pipelines
are designed to work
with loading very large datasets.
Because the data pipeline
only loads data into memory
in small chunks, it can work
with infinitely large datasets.
TensorFlow provides a lot of the plumbing
for setting up a data
pipeline, but you still have
to write a good bit of code yourself.
The code will use
TensorFlow-specific functions
which means you usually
can't take advantage
of other Python data processing libraries
that would make the job easier.
The big advantage of
building a data pipeline
is that you can take advantage
of parallel processing
across multiple CPUs.
You can have several threads
running at the same time
to load and preprocess data.
This means that the training
process doesn't have
to stop and wait while the
next chunk of data is loaded
for the next training pass.
This can make training much more efficient
with large datasets.
Let's take a look at a
typical data pipeline.
Let's say our dataset
is made up of hundreds
of separate CSV files.
The first step is to create
a list of all the file names
of the data files that
need to be processed.
Next, we shuffle the file
names into a random order
and add the file names into
a file processing queue.
Next, individual file names will be pulled
out of the file processing queue and sent
to the CSV file reader.
The CSV reader will parse the
raw data out of the CSV file
and break it up into individual records.
From there, each record in the CSV file
is fed into the record decoder.
The record decoder pulls out and formats
the individual values from each record.
And finally, we'll queue up
each record in the data queue
where it's ready to be fed into
your neural network for training.
TensorFlow provides functions
and helpers to help you build
each step of this pipeline,
and once you've built
the pipeline, TensorFlow
will execute it for you.
So which solution should you use?
I'd recommend choosing
the simplest solution
that works for your project.
If your dataset fits in the memory,
preload the entire dataset.
It require the least amount of code.
But if your dataset is huge,
then set up a data pipeline.
It's the most efficient way
to work with large datasets.
Data pipelines are especially common
for image-based datasets
since images take up
a lot of the memory.
Just think of building a data pipeline
as additional complexity
you only need to add
if other solutions won't work.
In this course, we'll be using preloading
to build a neural network,
since our data will fit into memory.