- [Instructor] For this
course I provided the data set
of video games sold by an
imaginary video game retailer.
We'll use this data to
train the neural network
that will predict how much money
we can expect future video games to earn
based on our historical data.
First, let's open up the data
and take a look at it in
the spreadsheet application.
The data is in a file called
sales_data_training.csv.
I've already opened it up
here in my spreadsheet application.
In this data set we have one
row for each video game title
that our store has sold in the past.
For each video game, we've
recorded several attributes.
First, we have critic_rating,
which is an average star
rating out of the five stars.
Next, is_action, which tells
us if this is an action game,
is_exclusive_to_us, which tells us
if we have an exclusive
deal to sell this game,
is_portable, which tells us
if this game runs on the
handheld video game player,
is_role_playing, which tells us
this is a role-playing game,
which is a genre of video games,
is_sequel, which tells us
this game was a sequel
of an earlier video game,
is_sports, which tells us
this is a sports video game,
suitable_for_kids, which tells us
this game is appropriate for all ages.
We also have total_earnings,
which is how much total money we earned
from selling this game to all customers,
and unit_price, which tells us
how much money one copy
of the game retailed for.
We'll use TensorFlow to
build the neural network
that tries to predict the
total earnings of a new game,
based on these characteristics.
Along with this file, we
also have a second data file
called sales_data_test.csv.
I'm going to open it in the spreadsheet,
so we're going to flip to that now.
Here we go.
This file is exactly like the first one,
it just has different data.
I've gone ahead and split the data
into a training data
set and a test data set.
The machine learning
system will only get to see
the training data set
during the training phase.
Then we'll use this test
data to check the accuracy
of the predictions from
our neural network.
Let's open up load_data.py,
and write the code to load this data.
Let's flip to PyCharm,
and we'll open up 03, load_data.py.
First, we're going to use pandas
to read the training data.
Pandas is a Python
library that makes it easy
to load data into memory
and work with the data
as if it were in a virtual spreadsheet.
You can do many of the same things
as you do with a spreadsheet,
like sorting data,
pulling out specific columns of data,
or applying calculations.
Our training data set is
stored in the file called
sales_data_training.csv.
We can load it by calling
the pandas read csv function,
pd.read_csv, and passing in
the file name we want to load,
sales_data_training.csv.
Pandas will then load the
data into a DataFrame.
To prevent a warning from
showing up at runtime,
we can also pass in a dtype parameter,
to tell it explicitly what
type of data we are loading,
so I'll pass in dtype=float,
to tell it we are expecting
floating-point numbers.
Next we need to split the
training data into two groups,
the X group is data about each video game
that we'll pass into the neural network,
and the Y group are the
values we want to predict.
In this case, that's how much money
we think each video game will earn.
Let's start on line 9.
To create the X training data,
we'll take all the columns
in the training data,
and simply drop the total_earnings column.
That will give us all the columns
except the one we don't want.
So we'll call training_data_df.drop,
and we'll pass in the name
of the column to drop,
total_earnings.
Then we also need to pass
in an axis=1 parameter
that tells it we want to
drop a column and not a row.
Finally, we'll call .values
to get back the result as an array.
To create the Y array,
we will only grab the
total_earnings column,
so we'll call training_data_df,
and then we'll pass in
the total_earnings column,
and then we'll call .values
to get the result as an array.
Now we need to repeat
the exact same process
to load the test data set.
Again, we'll use pandas read_csv
function to load the data.
So on line 13,
pd.read_csv,
and we'll pass in the name of the file,
sales_data_test.csv,
and we'll in dtype=float.
And again, we'll drop
the total_earnings column
to get the X array, so
we'll say, on line 16,
x_testing = test_data_df.drop,
and we'll pass in the name
of the column to drop,
total_earnings,
and axis=1,
and finally we'll call .values
to get the result as an array,
and we'll pull out the
total_earnings column
to create the Y array, test_data_df,
and pass in the name of the
column to grab, total_earnings,
and then we'll call .values
to get the result as an array.
Now we need to pre-process our data.
In order to train the neural network,
we want to scale all the numbers
in each column of our data set
to be between the value of 0 and 1.
If the numbers in one column are large
but the numbers in
another column are small,
the neural network training
won't work very well.
One way we can do this
is to use the MinMaxScaler object
from the popular scikit-learn library.
It's designed for exactly this purpose.
So on line 21, first we'll
create a new MinMaxScaler.
We just need to pass in a
feature_range parameter,
which tells it that we want all numbers
scaled between 0 and 1.
So we'll say feature_range=
and then pass in a tuple (0, 1),
and then we'll do the same
thing for the Y_scaler
MinMaxScaler(feature_range=(0, 1))
To actually scale our data,
we call the fit_transform
function on the scaler object,
and pass in the data we want to scale.
The result will be the rescaled data.
So on line 25, we'll call
X_scaler.fit_transform,
and we'll pass in X_training
as the data to scale.
And then we'll do the same
for the Y_scaled_training data on line 26.
We'll say Y_scaler.fit_transform,
and we'll pass in the Y_training data.
Fit_transform means we want
it to first fit to our data,
or figure out how much
to scale down the numbers in each column,
and then we want it to actually transform,
or scale the data.
Now we need to scale the
test data in the same way.
We want to make sure the test data
is scaled by the same
amount as the training data.
So in this case,
we'll just call transform
on each scaler object,
instead of fit_transform.
So on line 29, we'll
call X_scaler.transform,
and we'll pass in the X_testing data,
and then on line 30, Y_scaler.transform,
and we'll pass in the Y_testing data.
And now our data is ready
to pass in the TensorFlow.
The scaler scales the data
by multiplying it by a constant number
and adding a constant number.
At the bottom here, I printed
out how the Y data was scaled.
We can get these values
by looking at the
Y_scaler.scale_[0] Object,
and the Y_scaler.min[0] Object.
This will be useful to know later,
when we want to make predictions
with the neural network
and be able to unscale the data
back to the original units.
Okay, we should run the
code to make sure it works.
But before we run it,
I noticed I've made a
small mistake on line 9.
I wrote total_earning, but
there should be an s on that.
It should be total_earnings.
Let's add an s.
Okay, right click and run.
And we can see that the data
was scaled by these two values.