- [Instructor] Alright, let's build
a neural network with TensorFlow.
Our training data set
has nine input features,
so we'll need nine inputs
in our neural network.
We can model that with
a placeholder called X
that holds nine values.
Then, let's have three layers
in their neural network
that will train to find
the relationship between
the inputs and the output.
There are many different
types of layers you can use
in the neural network,
but we're going to use
the most straightforward type,
a fully connected neural network layer.
That means that every node in each layer
is connected to every node
in the following layer.
The first layer will have 50 nodes,
the second layer will have 100 nodes,
and the third layer will
have 50 nodes again.
To me, these layer sizes seem
like a good starting point,
but it's just a guess.
Once the neural network is coded
we can test out different layer sizes
to see what layer size
gives us the best accuracy.
And since we are trying
to predict a single value,
we'll have an output
layer with just one node,
that will be out prediction.
Let's open up model.py and create
a neural network with this
structure and TensorFlow.
Open model.py.
Here at the top of the file we've already
loaded our dataset and we're ready to
define the neural network
starting on line 38.
First, let's define
variables with how many
input and output nodes we'll have.
That'll make it easy to adjust
these numbers later if needed.
So we'll have nine input
nodes, so put nine.
On line 39 we'll have
one output, so put one.
Let's also create variables for
how many nodes we want in each
layer of our neural network.
So on line 42 for layer
one nodes we'll have 50,
and for layer two nodes we'll have 100.
And then for layer three
nodes we'll have 50 again.
Now we are ready to start building
the neural network itself.
First, let's define the input layer
of our neural network starting on line 49.
To keep things organized it's helpful
to put each layer of our neural network
in its own variable scope.
Normally in Python we organize our code
by creating new functions.
In TensorFlow we can
create variable scopes
by using the tf.variablescope
function instead.
Any variables we create within this scope
will automatically get a
prefix of input to their name
internally in TensorFlow.
TensorFlow has the ability
to generate diagrams
of the computational graph.
By putting our nodes into scopes
it helps TensorFlow generate
more useful diagrams
that are easier to understand.
Everything within the same scope
will be grouped together
within the diagram.
Our neural network should accept
nine floating point numbers
as the input for making predictions.
But each time we want a new prediction
the specific values we
pass in will be different.
So we can use a placeholder
node to represent that.
So for X the input to our
neural network, on line 50,
will be a tf.placeholder object.
When we create a new
node we need to tell it
what type of tensor it will accept.
The data we are passing into our network
will be floating point numbers,
so we'll tell it to inspect
the tf.float32 object.
We also need to tell it the size
or the shape of the tensor to expect.
For the shape of the input,
we use None, number_of_inputs.
So we'll say shape= and then a tuple,
None, number_of_inputs.
None tells TensorFlow our neural network
can mix up batches of any size
and number_of_inputs tells it to expect
nine values for each record in the batch.
We already defined number_of_inputs above.
Now, let's define the first
layer of our neural network.
We'll start with a new
variable scope on line 53.
We'll call this one layer_1.
Variable scope names
can't have spaces in them
so we can use an underscore instead.
Now, we can define the layer itself.
Each fully connected layer of
the neural network has three parts.
A weight value for each
connection between each node
and the nodes in the previous layer.
A bias value for each node,
and an activation function that outputs
the result of the layer.
First, we need variables to store
the bias values for each node.
This will be a variable
instead of a placeholder
because we want TensorFlow to
remember the value over time.
To create a variable we
can call tf.getvariable
and pass in the name.
Let's do that on line 55 for biases.
Tf.getvariable.
And we'll pass in name=, and use biases1.
Next, we need to pass in
the shape of this variable.
There's one bias value for
each node in this layer,
so the shape should be the same as
the number of nodes in the layer.
We define that above as Layer_1_nodes.
So we'll say shape=,
and then we'll pass in
the size as Layer_1_nodes.
We also need to tell TensorFlow
the initial value of this variable.
We can tell TensorFlow how
to set the initial value
of a variable by passing
it one of TensorFlow's
built-in initializer functions.
We want the bias values for
each node to default to zero,
so I'll pass in the inititalizer function
of tf.zeros_initializer
as the initializer to use.
So we'll pass in initializer=,
and pass in tf.zeros_initializer.
Next let's create a variable to hold
the weights for this layer.
Again we'll the tg.get_variable
to create a variable.
Let's do this on line 54.
Tf.get_variable.
We'll pass in the name weight1.
Name equals weight1.
We also need to give
this variable a shape.
This part's a little tricky.
We want to have one weight
for each node's connection
to each node in the previous layer.
So we can define the shape like this.
We'll say shape equals, and as an array,
one side of the array
will be number of inputs,
and the other side will be layer_1_nodes.
And finally, we need to set
the variable initializer.
With neural networks, a lot
of research has gone into
the best initial values
to use for weights.
A good choice is an algorithm
called Xavier initialization.
TensorFlow has a built-in
xavier_initializer function
so we can use that.
So we'll pass in initializer=,
tf.contrib.layers.xavier_initializer.
The last part of defining this layer
is multiplying the weights by the inputs
and calling an activation function.
TensorFlow is very flexible here
and let's you do this in any way you want.
We're going to do this on line 56.
We're going to use matrix multiplication
and a standard rectified linear unit
or relu activation function.
We can do this by first calling tf.matmul
for matrix multiplication.
And we'll multiply the inputs, X,
by the weights in this layer.
To that we'll add the biases,
and we'll wrap that with a
call to the relu function.
Tf.nn.relu, and then parenthesis.
If you're not familiar with the
math behind neural networks,
this might not be familiar to you,
but this is how you define the standard
fully-connected neural network.
Alright, we can define the
second layer in a similar way.
So first I'll copy the
definition of layer one,
and then I'm going to
paste it under layer two,
I'm going to hold down shift
and select the first three lines
and paste it here just to
maintain the formatting.
And now we need to change
all the ones to twos.
Weights1 equals weights2.
Layer_1_nodes is layer_2_nodes and so on.
Biases2.
Layer_2_nodes.
Change the output to layer_2_output.
We also need to change
the shape of the weights
so the input now is the output
from the previous layer.
So here we'll use layer_1_nodes
instead of number of inputs.
And then when we calculate the output,
instead of multiplying X,
which is the initial input,
we want to multiply by the previous layer.
So we'll multiply by layer_1_output.
Then we can define the
third layer in the same way,
so we'll copy the definition of layer two.
And again I'll hold shift
and go down three lines and paste
to maintain the formatting.
And I'll change all the twos to threes.
Weights3, change layer_1_nodes
to layer_2_nodes in this case.
Layer_2_nodes to layer_3_nodes.
Biases3, layer_3_nodes, the
output will be layer_3_output,
and in this case we'll be
multiplying the weights
for this layer by the
output for layer two,
so here we'll use layer_2_output.
Now we're ready to
define the output layer.
It's similar but slightly different.
So we'll start by again
copying the layer 3 definition
and pasting it the same way
to maintain the formatting.
We'll call it weights4 and biases4,
and we'll change layer_two_nodes
to layer_three_nodes,
but instead of having the
shape be layer_four_nodes,
we're going to use the
number_of_outputs variable
that we defined earlier since
this is the final layer.
And the same for the biases.
Then again we want to multiply
the weights from this layer
by the output from layer three.
So change that.
And then for the final output,
instead of calling it layer_three_output,
let's just call it prediction.
Since this is the final
output from our network,
that'll make it easier to follow.
Right now we have the entire
neural network defined,
but we don't have any way to train it yet.
To be able to train it
we need a cost function.
A cost function, also
called a lost function
tells us how wrong the neural network is
when trying to predict the correct output
for a single piece of training data.
Let's define the cost function
First on line 78 we have
another scope called cost.
Next, we'll define Y, a
node for the expected value
that we'll feed in during training.
Just like the input values
it will be a placeholder node
because we'll feed in
a new value each time.
So we'll create a tf.placeholder node.
The type will be floating point again,
so we'll use tf.float32.
And for the shape in this
case we'll pass in None, 1
since there's just one single output.
Shape equals None, 1.
Next we need to calculate the cost.
To measure the cost we'll
calculate the mean squared error
between what the neural network predicted
and what we expected it to calculate.
To do that we'll call the
tf.squared_difference function
and pass in the actual predication
and the expected value.
So tf.squared_difference, and
we'll pass in our prediction
which we defined above.
And our expected value, which is Y.
That will give us the square difference.
To turn it into a mean square difference,
we want to get the average
value of that difference.
So we'll wrap that with a call
to the reduce_mean function
which will do that for us.
So we'll wrap that with
a call to tf.reduce_mean.
And that's it.
The very last step is to
create an optimizer operation
that TensorFlow can call
to train the network.
As usual, let's create a new
scope starting on line 85.
We can call this one train.
To define an optimizer,
we just need to call
one of the optimizers
supplied by TensorFlow.
One of the standard optimizers
that's very powerful
is called the Adam optimizer.
To use it just call
tf.train.AdamOptimizer.
We just need to pass in the learning rate
which we've already pre-defined above.
Next, we need to tell it which variable
we want it to minimize.
So we'll pass in our cost function
as the value to minimize call.
So we'll call .minimize,
and we'll pass in cost.
That tells TensorFlow
that whenever we tell it
to execute the optimizer,
it should run one iteration
of the Adam optimizer in an attempt
to make the cost value smaller.
And that's it, now our neural
network is fully defined.