- [Instructor] Let's
open up training_loop.py
from the exercise files.
Once you have loaded your data
set and defined your model,
you're ready to create a
training loop to train the model.
Here, we've already defined the variable
called training_epochs on line 38.
An epoch is another name
for one full training pass
over the training data set.
This means we will do 100
iterations in our training loop
to train our neural network.
Okay, let's get started building
the training loop itself.
Let's jump down to line 91.
To run any operation on
the TensorFlow graph,
you first need to create a session.
We can create a new session
by calling tf.Session.
Within a session, we can ask TensorFlow
to execute commands by
calling session.run.
Session.run, and then we
can pass in the command
we want TensorFlow to execute.
Those can either be global
commands that TensorFlow provides
or specific nodes in our
graph that we want to execute.
The first command we always run
is the built in command to tell TensorFlow
to initialize all variables in our graph
to their default values.
The command that's called
tf.global_variables_initializer.
Global.
Now that all the variables
in our graph are initialized,
we're ready to create our training loop.
To train our neural network,
we'll run its optimizer function
over and over in the loop,
either a fixed number of times
or until it hits an
accuracy level we want.
I've created the training loop on line 98.
This loop will execute 100 times.
Inside the loop we'll
tell TensorFlow to execute
a single training pass
over the training data
by calling the optimizer function.
We can do this by calling session.run
and then pass in a
reference to the operation
that we want to call.
In this case, that's
the optimizer operation
that we defined above.
The optimizer needs some
additional data to run.
It needs the training data
and the expected results
for this training pass.
In our computational graph,
we have a placeholder node called x
that accepts the training data
and a placeholder node called y
that accepts the expected results.
To feed values into a placeholder node,
we can pass them in as a
parameter called feed_dict.
So I'll say feed_dict equals...
The feed_dict param
accepts a Python dictionary
where we pass in the names
of the placeholder nodes
we want to feed data into,
and the values we want to feed in.
So let's pass in our
scaled training data as x
and our scaled expected output as y.
So I'll say x,
and we'll pass in x_scaled_training.
And then for y,
I'll pass in y_scaled_training.
On line 104,
let's print out a message each
time we do a training pass.
And then at the end on line 107,
let's print out the message
when training is complete.
All right, let's run the code.
Right click, choose run.
We can see that it runs
100 loops of training.
In the next section,
we'll go deeper into the training process
and monitoring the results.