- [Instructor] Do you
want to learn how to use
deep learning in your applications?
Google's TensorFlow is one
of the most popular tools
for deep learning.
With TensorFlow, you can build your own
state-of-the-art machine learning systems
and use them to power
your own applications.
Hi, I'm Adam Geitgey.
In this course, we will
learn how to use TensorFlow
to build and deploy
machine learning models.
First, we will cover how
to get TensorFlow installed
and running on your system.
Then, we will explore
how to create and train
a machine learning model in TensorFlow.
Next, we will use TensorFlow's
visualization tools
to analyze and improve our
machine learning model.
Finally we will deploy
the model to the cloud
where we can call it from any program.
If you want to learn how to
incorporate machine learning
methods in your own applications,
this is the right place to start.
Let's dive in.