- [Instructor] Now that we've
set up the the training loop,
it's time to get to the actual training.
Let's open up training.py.
Here we have a neural network
with a computational graph
and the basic training
loop already defined.
Let's run the code and see how it works.
Right-click.
Choose Run.
Great, the training seems to
have completed successfully.
But right now, we don't have a way to see
if the accuracy is improving
over time during training.
Let's add some code to display
how the training is progressing.
Every five training steps,
let's print out the current accuracy.
First, let's click to
minimize the console window.
Now, here on line 104,
let's add this line of code.
If epoch mod, that's the percent sign,
five,
equal equal zero:
this simply says that
for every five passes
in the training loop,
we want to do something.
To get the current accuracy,
we can run the neural
network's cost function
and print out the result.
So we'll call session.run and ask it
to call the cost function.
So we'll say training_cost,
equals,
and we'll call session.run,
then we'll pass in the cost function.
To call the cost function, we
need to pass in a feed dict
containing the training
data, so we'll say,
feed_dict equals,
and for X we'll pass in
the X-scaled training data,
and we'll do the same for Y,
passing in the Y-scaled training data.
And that will give us the current cost
with the training data.
We can also monitor the current
cost with the testing data
the same way, just by passing
in the testing data instead.
So we'll say testing_cost
equals session.run,
we'll pass in the cost function,
and then for the feed dict,
we'll pass in the X-scaled testing data
and the Y-scaled testing data this time.
So feed_dict equals,
for X we'll have X-scaled testing,
and for Y,
we'll have Y-scaled testing.
And now we'll print out those values.
We can do that with a
regular print statement.
So we'll say print(),
and then pass in epoch,
training_cost,
and testing_cost.
Great, that will give us
constant updates during training.
Once the training loop ends,
let's also print out a
final accuracy value.
We can do that exactly the same way.
Let's cut and paste above
where we have training
cost and testing cost.
So I'll highlight this, copy,
then I'll paste that at the bottom,
and tab it over,
but let's call these
values final_training_cost
and final_testing_cost.
Great, and let's print those values out
so we can see what they are.
So we'll say print("Final Testing Cost"),
and then to format the string,
I'll just call Python's format function
and pass in the value, so
let's say final_testing_cost,
and we can cut and paste
this and do the same thing
for the training cost.
Just change the values.
Training cost, and final,
training cost.
Let's run the code and see how it works.
Right-click and choose run.
And let's scroll up to the
top of the output here.
We can see how the cost
decreases at each step
in the training process,
all the way down towards the end.
That means the neural network
is getting more accurate
over time with training.
And here's the final cost, 0.00011.
That's not bad.
You'll of course see a
slightly different value,
since there's randomness involved
with initializing and
training a neural network.
But your values should
be relatively close.