- [Instructor] In TensorFlow,
it can be difficult
to visualize exactly what's happening
during the training process.
Luckily, TensorFlow provides TensorBoard,
a web-based interface
that lets us visualize
and monitor our machine-learning model.
One of the most useful
features of TensorBoard
is that it lets us track the accuracy
of our model as it trains.
The first tab of TensorBoard
is called Scalars.
The term scalar here
just means a single value
as opposed to an array
of multiple numbers.
This is the section of TensorBoard
where you can log single values over time
and view the results as graphs.
Here, I have a chart
of the training process
for a neural network.
The chart shows the value of
the cost function over time
while training the neural network.
You can see that the cost starts high
and then goes down over
time until it levels off.
You can also see two lines here.
The blue line shows the accuracy
for the training dataset
and the orange line shows the accuracy
for the testing dataset.
You can also toggle each
line on and off here
with these checkboxes.
If you hover over a point on the graph,
you'll see that exact cost
values at that point in time.
Being able to visualize
your data is very helpful.
However, you have to tell TensorFlow
to log the values you want to visualize.
It won't automatically create
charts like this for you.
Let's see how to add
logging to a neural network.
Open up model_logging.py.
Here, we have already
defined our neural network
and the training loop.
Down here on line 124,
we're printing out the cost
to the console as we train.
But we're not saving any log files yet
so TensorBoard won't be
able to show anything.
In TensorFlow, we log values
by creating special
operations in our graph
called summary operations.
These operations take in the value
and create log data in a format
that TensorBoard can understand.
Then, we pass that summary data
to a TensorFlow file writer object
to save it to disk.
First, let's add the summary operation
to our computational graph
that will log the cost.
We'll do that up on line 91.
To keep things organized,
I've created a new variable scope
to hold our logging operations.
We've just called it logging.
Now, let's add in a
tf.summary.scalar object
that will represent the
value we are logging.
So we'll say, tf.summary.scalar.
To log the value, we pass in the name,
let's call this current_cost,
and then, a reference
to the operation to log.
In this case, cost.
So why did we use a
tf.summary.scalar object?
A scalar is just a single number
so that's what you want to use
to log a single value like this.
TensorFlow also supports
logging more complex objects
like histograms, pictures,
and even sound files
but most of the time, you'll
be logging single numbers.
We can run this node by
calling session.run on it
just like any other node in our graph.
Running it will generate the log data
in the right format.
But while running this
node directly is easy
when you only have one metric,
sometimes you'll want to
log many different metrics.
It can be tedious to
have to call session.run
on every single metric so
TensorFlow has a shortcut.
We're going to define a new node
of type tf.summary.merge_all.
So we'll say summary equals
tf.summary.merge_all.
When you run this special node,
it'll automatically execute
all the summary nodes in your graph
without you having to
explicitly list them all.
It's just a helper that makes life easier.
Now, let's move down to the
training loop on line 104.
We also need to create the log
files to save this data to.
We can do that by creating a
tf.summary.FileWriter object.
First, we'll create one to
write out our training accuracy.
So we'll say, training_writer equals
tf.summary.FileWriter.
You just need to pass in
the name of the folder
you want to save the file to.
I'm going to use /logs/training.
And then, we need to pass in the reference
to our computational graph,
that's just session.graph.
And then, we'll create a separate file
the same way to save our testing accuracy.
So that's tf.summary.FileWriter.
In this case, we'll use
the path of /logs/testing.
And then, again, we'll
pass in session.graph.
Notice that I put both log file
in the same logs subfolder.
If you put multiple log files
in the same top-level folder,
TensorBoard will show them all together
and let you flip between them.
Next, let's go down to
where we were displaying
the accuracy of our model on line 117.
We need to add in calls
to run our new summary operation here
but instead of adding
two new lines of code,
we can just update these two lines.
We can ask TensorFlow to
run more than one operation
in the same session.run statement.
So we'll change this parameter from cost
to an array of cost, summary.
Now, session.run will return two results
so we can capture the new result
in the variable called training_summary.
This is telling TensorFlow
to run both operations at the same time
and we're capturing both results
in the two different variables.
Since both operations need
the same input data anyway,
this is more efficient.
Now, let's do the same
thing for testing_summary.
So we'll change cost to cost, summary.
And then, we'll capture the result
in a variable called testing_summary.
Great, now we have the data stored
in the training_summary and
testing_summary variables.
The last step is to write
that data into our log files.
We'll do that below on line 121.
We'll call training_writer
and we'll call .add_summary.
We'll pass in the training_summary
variable we just created
and then we need to pass in
the current epoch number.
This will be the X axis in out graph.
We'll pass in epoch.
And now, let's do the same
thing for the testing_writer.
Testing_writer.add_summary.
We'll pass in the testing_summary
variable we just created.
And then, again, the epoch.
That's it, let's run the code
to generate the log files
that we can view in TensorBoard.
Right click, choose run.
Great, now let's look at
the result in TensorBoard.
To run TensorBoard, we'll
open up a terminal window
and navigate to the folder
where we've downloaded the example code.
In PyCharm, you can hover your mouse
on the bottom-left of the window
here, and then click Terminal
to open up a new system terminal window.
But if you prefer, you
can also open a standard
operating system terminal
window outside of PyCharm.
To run TensorBoard, we
just type tensorboard
and then we have to supply
a parameter called logdir
that tells it where to find the log files.
- -logdir equals, and now
we have to give it the path
where we saved the log
files in our program.
In this case, it's just 04/logs.
Note that on Windows,
you'll use backslashes
instead of forward slashes here.
And then hit Enter to run it.
Now, TensorBoard gives us a URL
to open up in our browser here.
Your URL will be slightly different.
Copy and paste the URL
and then open up in your web browser.
You might notice that the
port number in the URL
is always 6006.
That's because 6006 looks
kind of like G-O-O-G
or goog for Google.
Once TensorBoard opens,
click on the logging group.
Now, you'll see an interactive
chart for the metric.
You can expand the chart
by clicking on the expand icon here.
You can use this exact same process
to log and monitor any metric you want.
When you're done with TensorBoard,
you can close it by going
back to your terminal window
and hitting Ctrl+C.
So let's flip back to
PyCharm and hit Ctrl+C.