- [Instructor] So far, we've
built and trained the model.
Now, let's learn how to
save that model to a file,
so that we can reuse it later.
Open up model_checkpoints.py.
Here, we have the code to define
and train the neural network.
But, after the file runs,
the neural network isn't saved anywhere.
Let's go down to Line 95.
To save it, we first need to
create a tf.train.Saver object.
Let's put it here, under
the graph definition,
but before the training loop.
Tf
.train
.Saver.
This is the object we'll
use to save the model.
Now, at the very bottom of the
code, way down on Line 150,
let's go down there.
We can save the model.
To save the model, we just call saver.save
and pass in the session and the file name.
So, we'll call saver.save.
We'll pass in the session
and then the file name
where we want to save it.
I'll use log/trained_model.ckpt.
These files are called checkpoint files,
so they're usually named with
a .ckpt file name extension,
but that's not required.
Then, here on the next
line, we'll just print out
where the file was saved.
Okay, let's run the code.
Right-click and choose Run.
Great, the model was saved.
If we click here on the
logs folder, we can also see
that several new files were created.
Now, let's see how to use the saved model.
Let's close this file and
open up load_checkpoint.py.
Here we have the same
graph definition as before,
but down on Line 98,
you can see that there's no training loop.
Instead, let's go down to Line 104
and load our checkpoint file.
Just call saver.restore
and pass in the session and
the name of the file to load.
So, we'll say session
and the same file name,
logs/trained_model.ckpt.
Now, let's look above on Line 101.
I've commented out this
line for a good reason.
It's important that when
loading from a checkpoint,
you don't call
tf.global_variables_initializer.
Since all the variable values
are loaded from a file,
we don't want to initialize them
back to their default values.
Great, now we can use
the pretrain network,
just like before.
Let's run the code.
Right-click, choose Run,
and we can see that we
get the same result,
using the pretrain model loaded from disk.