- [Instructor] Alright, so you build
a great model in TensorFlow
and you want to deploy it
into a production environment.
What should you do?
Well, one of the best
features of TensorFlow
is that we can take a model
we've built, like this one,
and export it to a file
and then run that file
on Google's cloud servers.
That let's us scale up any
machine learning feature
we've built to an almost infinite scale
without having to
maintain our own servers.
But in order to do that
we have to tell Google
how we want to run our
model in production.
Let's take a closer look at
this model in TensorBoard.
There's several ways
we can use this model.
First, if we want to
initialize all the variables
to their default values,
we call this init operator.
If we want to generate
an output we can pass
an input data and then
call the output operation.
And if we want to train the network
we can call the train operator.
If we export this model to
a file using the normal way
of saving model checkpoint files,
Google won't know which
function we want to run.
Instead, we need to export
this model a special way
where define exactly
what the start in point
of the model is that we want to run.
Let's take a look.
Let's switch to PyCharm
and let's open up
export_model_for_cloud.py.
Here we've defined our model
with a normal computational
graph and a training loop.
At the end of the training loop
we want to export the train model,
but because we want to use
the model in the cloud,
we can't use the normal
tf.train.saver function
to save the model.
Instead, we're going to use
TensorFlow's saved model builder
that let's us customize
how the model is exported.
First, let's go all the
way down to line 149.
Now, let's create a new
saved model builder object.
The full name is
tf.saved_model.builder.SavedModelBuilder.
The only parameter we have
to pass in is the name
of the folder we want to
save the model file to.
I'm going to use exported model.
Now we're ready to define
the inputs and outputs
of the model that we want Google to use
when it runs the model in the cloud.
First, we have a Python dictionary
with a key called inputs.
In this dictionary, we'll list each tensor
that needs to be filled in
when their model is run.
Our model takes in one tensor
with nine values as input,
so that means our model
will have one input.
We'll just call it input.
For the value of the input key,
we'll pass in the tensor
we want data fed into.
In this case, it will be X,
but to make this work we
also need to wrap that tensor
in the call to a function called
tf.saved_model.utils.build_tensor_info,
like this,
and then pass in X.
Okay, now let's define
the output the same way.
Our output is a single
tensor with one value.
Let's call the output earnings
and pass in the prediction
tensor as the tensor to output.
Again we'll make the call to
tf.saved_model.utils.build_tensor_info
and pass in prediction.
Next, on line 158, we have to define
what TensorFlow calls a signature def.
A signature def is sort of like a function
or method declaration in
the programming language.
We're telling TensorFlow
that to run the model
it should call a certain
function with certain parameters.
We create the signature
def by calling this
tf.saved_model.signature_def_utils.build_signature_def
then we'll pass in the inputs
and outputs we just defined.
So the inputs will be
the inputs dictionary
and the outputs will be
the outputs dictionary.
Then we have to name the
method we are defining,
but we won't make up a name,
we'll always use the special
predefined function name called
tf.saved_model.signature_constants.PREDICT_METHOD_NAME.
That's the name Google
will always look for
in order to execute our model.
Great, we've defined the inputs,
the outputs, and the signature def.
Now we're ready to
configure the model builder
to tell it exactly how we
want this model exported.
Let's go down to line
164 and then we can call
the
model_builder.add_meta_graph_and_variables
function.
That names a mouthful, but
meta graph is the structure
of our computational
graph and the variables
are the values we set on
each node in the graph.
So this is telling TensorFlow
that we want to export everything.
Next, it takes in the session
and then the tag name which
is what Google looks for
when figuring out what to execute.
So it'll always be
tf.saved_model.tag_constants.SERVING.
Next, we create a signature def map
that lists all the signature
defs this model supports.
This map has an entry
with a magic name called
tf.saved_model.signature_constants.
DEFAULT_SERVING_SIGNATURE_DEF_KEY.
That long name is what
Google will be looking for.
That's it, all that's left to do
is call save on our model builder.
We'll do that on line 172
and now we can run the code.
Right-click and choose run.
We can see here in PyCharm
a new exported model folder
and inside is a file
called saved_model.pb.
This file contains the
structure of our model
in Google's special proto buff format.
There's also a variables
subfolder that contains
a checkpoint of all the
variables in our graph.
This model is now ready to be
uploaded to the Google cloud.