- [Instructor] To host
machine learning models
on the Google Cloud service
you need to set up your Google account.
We also need to install
the Google Cloud SDK.
The Google Cloud SDK contains utilities
that we can use to interact
with the Google Cloud
services from our computer.
First in your browser,
let's go to console.cloud.google.com.
Here log in with your Google account.
If you already have a Gmail account
you can use that email
address and password.
If you don't have a Google account
you'll be given the option
to create a new one.
This is the Google Cloud
platform dashboard.
From here you can access all
the different Google Cloud services.
If you don't have any projects,
you may see a button that
says create new project.
So you can click that.
If you do have projects,
just click on the project dropdown
and then click plus to
create the new project.
Name your project Tensor Flow Class.
You'll notice that the
project will also get assigned
a unique key like
tensorflowclass170621.
That's the ID you can
use to access the project
from your programs.
Now click create.
And we have to wait until it finishes.
You can watch the progress
in the notifications tray
in the top right.
Great the project's been created.
Since the Google Cloud
platform has so many features,
not all of them are enabled by default.
We need to enable Google
Cloud machine learning
before we can use it.
So click on the main menu on the left,
go to API manager, and
then choose library.
This is a list of all the
Google services you can enable.
Look for Google Cloud machine learning.
And under that look for the
machine learning engine API
and click on it.
If you've never used it before,
you'll have to click here to enable it.
If you've already enabled it
you'll see a screen like this.
Finally you need to provide
billing details for your account
before you can use some of
the features of Google Cloud.
To do that, click on the main menu
and then go to the billing section.
You might be offered the free trial
which you can take
advantage if you'd like.
Be aware that you're
responsible for any charges
that you incur on Google Cloud.
Great, now that we've created the project
and enabled the machine learning API's,
the account's ready to go.
The next step is to install
the Google Cloud SDK.
The Google Cloud SDK is a set of tools
that let us work with
the Google Cloud service
from our computer.
To do that, let's go to the
cloud.google.com/sdk/downloads.
On this page you'll be given
several installation options.
Choose the option for run
the interactive installer
to download and install
the latest release.
This will give you directions
for Mac and for Windows.
The directions are
different for each platform,
follow the instructions for
your platform to install it.
Once you have the Google
Cloud SDK installed,
we need to activate it by
logging in from the command line.
Open up the command line
window in your computer
and in that window type
gcloud init and hit enter.
Now the Google Cloud SDK will attempt
to open a web browser window
to the Google login page
when we hit enter.
Choose the correct account
and then click Allow.
Once you see this message
you are now authenticated
with the Google Cloud SDK,
everything is ready to go.