- [Instructor] The advantage
of hosting your model
in the Google Cloud
is that it is accessible
from anywhere in the world.
Google servers will run the model,
and you are only charged based on
how many requests are made.
It's a great option for using
a TensorFlow model in production
if you don't want to
maintain your own servers.
Let's learn how to upload
a custom TensorFlow model
to the Google Cloud ML service.
Before we get started,
make sure you have already
exported the model as a .pb file.
You can do that by running
export_model_for_cloud final in PyCharm,
if you haven't already.
Also, make sure that you have
a properly configured
Google Cloud account,
with access to the
Google Cloud ML service,
and that you have the
gcloud command line tool
already installed.
You can review the previous video
if you don't have those
two things available yet.
I have my machine learning
model exported here,
to the exported_model subfolder.
To use this model in the
Cloud, it's a two-step process.
First, we'll upload the model files
to a Google Cloud storage bucket.
Then, we'll create a new Google
Cloud machine learning model
using the files we've uploaded.
Once the model is in the Cloud,
we can use it by sending it data.
I've included a sample data file here
called sample_input_prescaled.json.
This data is a simple JSON file
with the name of the model's input,
and then the values you
want to feed into the model.
To work with the Google Cloud service,
we're going to use the command line.
Open up a Terminal
window on your computer,
and then navigate to the folder
where your model is exported.
In my case, that's
Desktop/Exercise\ Files/06/.
Now we can upload the model files
to a Google Cloud storage bucket.
We'll do that with this command.
Here, we're calling gsutil.
Gsutil is a utility that handles
lots of basic Google Service operations,
like creating new storage buckets,
moving files around, changing
permissions, and so on.
mb stands for "Make bucket."
Next, we have to tell
Google which data center
to create the bucket in.
Google has data centers
all over the world,
and you have to tell them
which one you want to use.
I used us-central1,
which is located in Iowa
in the United States.
You can use that one, too.
Then, we have to name the storage bucket.
These names have to be unique
across the entire world,
so you'll have to use a slightly
different name than mine.
Change the number at the
end to something else,
but remember what you chose.
Okay, hit enter.
And the bucket was created.
Next, we need to upload our
model files into the bucket.
We'll do that with this command.
Again, we're using gsutil.
cp means we want to copy files
from our computer to the Cloud.
- R means we want to
copy files recursively,
so all the subfolders
that we have are included
when they're uploaded.
Then we tell it what folder to upload,
and then we have to
tell it where to upload.
Here, you should put in the
same bucket name as before,
and then a subfolder of earnings_v1/,
and hit Enter.
Great, our model files are
now stored on Google servers.
Next, we have to tell the
Google Machine Learning Engine
that we want to create a new model.
We can do that with this command.
Here, we're using the gcloud tool
to call the ml-engine service.
Inside of that service,
we're asking it to create
a model with models create.
We're going to name that model earnings,
and we're asking it to create that model
in the same uscentral1 region.
Hit Enter, and the model
was created successfully.
If you receive an error in this step,
make sure you've enabled
the ml-engine service
inside the Google console.
We've created the named model
in the Google Cloud
Machine Learning service,
but the model is just
an empty placeholder.
The Google Cloud Machine Learning service
lets you upload multiple
versions of the same model.
To actually use a model,
we need to upload the
first version of the model.
Let's try to create a named version.
We'll use the gcloud tool again.
Here, we're using gcloud
to call the ml-engine.
We're asking it to create a new version.
We're calling the version v1.
We're telling it that the
model's name is earnings,
and we're telling it
where to find the files
to use to create this version.
This is the same location
where we just uploaded the files earlier.
Now we'll hit Enter, and this
might take a few minutes.
Great, our model is now live in the Cloud,
and ready to be used.
We can try out our model
by using the gcloud predict command.
Here we're calling gcloud.
We're asking it to talk
to the ml-engine service,
do the predict function,
the model we want to call is earnings,
and the data we want to feed in
is the sample_input_prescaled.json
file we saw earlier.
And hit Enter.
Great, our model just made
a prediction from the Cloud.
Now we can access the model
from anywhere in the world,
and it will run from Google's servers.
There are several ways we can
use our Cloud-based model.
If you want to make a few
predictions on a small dataset,
you can just use the gcloud
command, like we've done here.
If you want to make predictions
for thousands or millions of items,
you can upload a data file
to a Cloud storage bucket
and then use the gcloud command
to make predictions from that data file.
You can also use the Google
Cloud API Client Library
for any programming language
to make calls to your model
from any other program.