- [Instructor] Now that
we have created the
cloud based machine learning
model, let's put it to use.
If you haven't already
created the cloud based model,
please review the previous
video before continuing.
In this video, we'll learn how to call
our machine learning model
from a Python program.
But you can also use
the same approach to use
cloud based machine learning models
in programs not written in Python.
Google provides implementations
of its API client library
for many popular programming languages.
Let's take a look at
developers.google.com/apiclientlibrary
and let's scroll down to
the supported languages.
You can call Google services from
any of these languages, using the same
basic approach we'll use here.
Just check the documentation
and code samples
provided by Google, to see how the syntax
varies for each language.
Okay, let's get started,
to use a cloud based
machine learning model
from another program,
we need two things, first, we need access
to make calls to the cloud.
For this, we need a credentials file.
This file keeps our cloud based
service secure from unauthorized use.
Second, we need to write the code
to call our cloud based model, for that,
we'll use the Google
cloud API client library.
Let's set up the credentials file.
In your web browser, open
up the Google console,
at console.cloud.google.com,
if you aren't already
logged in, just log back in and then,
double check on the toolbar, to make sure
you have the correct project selected.
Now in the menu, we're going to look at
API manager and then, credentials.
Then on the dropdown menu
next to create credentials,
we're going to choose service account key.
Here, we need to choose
which service account to use.
We're going to use the default
service account for convenience.
But you can also create
a new service account
with limited permissions if
you're concerned about security.
Now, click create.
The credentials file will be
downloaded to your computer.
Let's look at the file on our computer,
show in finder, and now,
let's rename this file.
I'm going to right click and choose rename
and then call it, credentials.json,
just to make it simple.
Now I'm going to copy
this file into PyCharm
by right clicking and choosing copy,
and then going to PyCharm
and then right clicking
on the 06 folder and pasting it,
and then, click okay.
Now, open up call_cloud_service.py.
This file uses the Google
cloud services API client
to make request to our cloud based model.
First, put in your project ID on line five
where it says, change me.
You can check your project ID by
going back to your web browser
and clicking on Google cloud platform,
to go back to the dashboard and then,
looking under project info.
This is my project ID,
I'm going to copy that
and go back to PyCharm and paste that in.
On the next line, make sure the model name
matches the name you use
to create your model.
My model's called, earnings.
Now let's look at line 10, this is where
we put in the data we want to use as input
to our machine learning model.
I've hard coded some example
data here that we can try,
but in the real program,
you might feed in user input
or read this data from a file.
The rest of the code
here, is the minimum code
needed to make request to
the Google cloud ML service.
First, on line 15, we read
the account credentials
from the json file, we
need this to have access
to make a call to the cloud service.
Then, on line 16, we
create the Python object
to connect to the cloud ML service.
Next on line 19, we
format our project name,
into the format that Google expects.
And then, on line 20, we
make a predictionary quest,
where we connect to the service
and send it our input data.
And then, on line 26, we check for errors
and as long as everything looks good,
then on line 30, we get the response.
And finally on line 33,
we print the results.
Now, let's run the code and try it out.
Right click, choose run.
Great, we're able to successfully connect
to our machine learning model in the cloud
and use it to make a prediction.
Now we can call this
machine learning model
from inside of any program we write.