- [Narrator] It's always
helpful to visualize
what's happening with your data.
This is where TensorBoard comes in.
It takes what we do in TensorFlow
and creates a graphical
representation of it.
Before we can open up TensorBoard,
we need some log files to look at.
Let's open up train_model.py
and let's run it.
When we run it, this will
train the neural network
and save log files that we'll be able
to view with TensorBoard.
Right click, choose run.
You can see here in Pycharm
the new logs folder has been
created with the log files.
Alright, lets run TensorBoard.
To run TensorBoard, let's
open up a Terminal window.
In Pycharm you can hover
your mouse on the bottom left
and then click Terminal,
but if you prefer, you
can also open the standard
operating system Terminal
window outside of Pycharm.
To run TensorBoard, type TensorBoard
and then --logdir.
And we'll give the folder
where our logs are written,
in this case, 05/logs,
note that on Windows,
you'll use backslashes
instead of forward slashes.
Now hit enter, now
TensorBoard gives us a URL.
Copy that URL and open
it in your web browser.
To see our computational graph,
click on the graphs tab at the top.
This is a visual representation
of our computational graph.
Each variable scope or
operation in our neural network
is represented by a box in this diagram.
Here is the input layer
of our neural network,
which is connected to layer
one, and then layer two,
and layer three, and then
finally to the output layer.
Note that layer one, two,
and three are all blue.
That means these boxes have
the same internal structure,
so at a glance, we can
tell that all three layers
perform the same basic
operations on the data.
Now, let's zoom in to the
connections between those.
Each line represents a
tensor or a ray of data
being passed between the nodes.
We can see that the input layer
passes nine values to the first
layer of the neural network.
That makes sense, because
we have nine input features
in the neural network.
The first number represented here
with a question mark is the batch size.
The batch size can vary each time,
so that's why it's shown
as a question mark.
If we followed the line
to the output layer,
we can see that the output
layer returns a single number.
This is the final prediction
from our neural network.
We can also zoom in to each
node to see more detail.
Let's go back in the input node
and we'll click to expand
it on the plus sign.
You can see that inside the input layer
is the placeholder value we pass in,
let's take a look at a
more complicated node.
Let's open up layer one.
Click and expand, and
we'll zoom out a little bit
so we can see it better.
This shows us exactly what is happening
inside a layer of the neural network.
The input values feed in here
and then their matrix
multiplied by the weights,
then the bias value is added,
and then a ReLU, a
rectified linear activation
function is applied and the result
is sent to the next layer.
Finally, let's take a
look at the cost node.
Let's zoom out, go to the
cost node, and expand it.
We can see that the output
of the neural network
feeds into the cost function,
where the current cost of the
neural network is calculated.
We can also see here that the
value is saved as a metric
called, current cost.
If we look at a scalars
tab, we'll be able to
see the graph for this metric.
Let's take a look.
And here's that metric.
Alright, let's switch
back to the graphs tab,
and zoom back out, and close these notes.
Another great feature of TensorBoard,
is the ability to trace the
path of data through the graph.
Let's say we want to see what is required
to generate the output.
Click on the output node and then
click this trace input slider.
This highlights exactly
the path data flows through
to generate the output
of the neural network.
This is a very helpful
way to debug a graph
if things aren't working as expected.
If we click on the cost node,
we can see how the display changes.
So we can see the path of data
used to generate the costs.
If we click over here on the
init node, on the right side,
this shows us which
nodes will be initialized
when we start a new session in our graph.
TensorBoard is a great tool for exploring
the structure of your models
and understanding how data flows.
It's also very helpful for debugging.
Click around and get a feel
for how things are connected.
Try comparing what you see here
with the code and train_model.py
and see if you can figure
out where each connection
in the diagram comes from.
When you're done, you
can close TensorBoard
by going back to the Terminal window
and hitting Control + C.