- [Instructor] When you are building
machine learning models with TensorFlow,
you'll be spending a lot
of time training the model
and then repeating the training process
with different parameters
to see what works best.
Using TensorBoard we can visually monitor
the progress of training as it happens,
and even compare different
training runs against each other.
Let's see how it works.
First, let's open up
visualize_training.py.
Here we already have our
computational graph defined
and we have a training loop defined.
And down here on line 104,
we've defined the training filewriter
and a testing filewriter
that will write out log
files during training
that we can then view in TensorBoard.
Let's say that we want to retrain
this neural network several times,
with a different number of nodes
in the first layer each time.
Our goal is to find out
which neural network design
gives us the best prediction accuracy.
The problem is that each time
we run the training process,
additional log files will be created
with the same name as the old log files.
The new log files will
mix with the old log files
and create overlapping
graphs in TensorBoard.
We won't have any way to tell
which training run was which.
We can fix this by using
a different run name
for each training run.
Here's how it works.
First, if you already have a
logs folder here in PyCharm,
let's right click and delete the folder
before we get started.
Right click, delete, and click delete.
Okay, let's go up to line 37.
Let's create the variable called RUN_NAME.
This will just be a string
where we can give a name to
the current training run.
Let's start with "run 1 with 50 nodes".
Now let's go back down to line 104.
Currently every log file is
named exactly the same way.
Let's change how we are
creating the log file names,
so that we can separate them per run.
All we have to do is put each
run in a different subfolder.
To do that, let's add in run name
to the path where we are
saving the log files.
So here I'll add slash
and then the placeholder,
and then I'll substitute
that in by calling .format
and passing in the run name.
And we'll do the same thing
for the testing writer.
.format, and pass in the run name.
Great, let's run the code and
then train the neural network.
Right click, and run.
Okay, let's check the folder in PyCharm.
We can see it created
the subfolder correctly.
Let's try tweaking our neural network
and doing a second run.
First, let's minimize the console
and go back to the top where
we defined our run name,
and let's call this one
"run 2 with 20 nodes".
And then let's edit the number of nodes
in the first layer to be 20.
Okay, let's run the code again
to train the neural network a second time.
Right click, run.
And now we have a second
folder in PyCharm.
Now let's open up TensorBoard
and see how these runs look.
Let's open up a terminal window.
Highlight in the bottom
left, click terminal.
And now we'll run TensorBoard
by typing tensorboard --logdir=05/logs
and if you're using Windows
you'll want to use the
backslash there instead,
and press enter.
When TensorBoard starts it will give you
a URL to open in your browser.
Copy and paste that into your web browser.
Okay, now click on
logging to see our charts
and let's click to expand the chart.
Right now there are
four lines on the chart,
but if you look at the bottom left,
you can see that each
run is listed separately.
We have lines for the testing data
and the training data of each run.
You can click here to
turn each line on or off.
You can also click toggle all runs
to turn them all on or off.
Let's compare the testing
results for the two runs.
Let me turn on just those two lines.
So we'll turn on run 2
testing and run 1 testing.
And we can also turn off
smoothing if you like.
As we trace the line here,
we can see that run 1
had a lower cost the
entire time than run 2.
So it looks like having 50
nodes in the first layer
is working better than having 20 nodes.
These graphs also update automatically
every minute as you train.
If you want, you can kick
off additional training runs
and watch the progress live on
this chart to quickly compare
how different neural network
designs work with this data.
Once you find the settings that work best,
you might want to export this data
to another program to create a report.
To do that, click the show
download data links button here.
That will enable a new selection
box in the bottom right.
You can choose a single run,
and then you can export it
as a csv file or a json file.
That file will have
each point in the chart
in the format you can easily
open in the spreadsheet.
When you're done, you
can close TensorBoard
by going back to the terminal
window and hitting CTRL+C.