- [Instructor] TensorBoard
allows you to create custom
visualizations beyond just line graphs.
You can use these visualizations
to monitor your machine
learning model and what kind
of data it's generating.
Currently TensorFlow supports
these types of visualizations.
First, the image visualization
allows you to see any
array of data as an image.
You create an image
visualization by adding
a tf.summary.image object
to your graph and passing it
the array you want to visualize.
This is helpful when you're
building a neural network
that classifies or generates images.
In this example I was training
a neural network to generate
new images from a data set.
Using the image visualization
in TensorBoard, I was able
to monitor the images the
system was generating during
the training process.
You can also listen to
audio data in TensorBoard.
To add an audio player to
TensorBoard, you create a new
tf.summary.audio object and you
add it to your computational
graph, this is typically used
when building models that
recognize speech or generate sounds.
It lets you hear the sound
files that your model
is processing.
You can also create interactive
histograms and distribution
graphs in TensorBoard.
When you add a
tf.summary.histogram object to your
computational graph, it creates
both a histogram like you
see here, and a distribution
graph which we'll see
in a little bit.
Histograms are a powerful way
to monitor ranges of values
over time, they show you
not only the range of values
in the array of data but they
can also display how these
data ranges vary through time.
Let's try adding a histagram
summary to a neural network
and see how it works.
Let's switch the PyCharm and let's open up
custom_visualization.py.
Here we've already defined
our computational graph
in the training loop.
And on line 93 we also
already have a scalar summary
defined that monitors the
cost of our neural network
as it's trained.
This will generate a line
chart that shows the neural
network getting more
accurate over time during
the training process.
But let's say we want to
visualize the actual predictions
that our neural network is
making during the training
process.
To do that, we can add a
histogram that monitors our
predictions.
Let's create a new
tf.summary.histogram node.
Tf.summary.histogram then
we'll pass in the name for our
node in this case we'll
use predicted value.
And then we pass in the node
in our graph that we want
to monitor, which will be prediction.
And that's all we have to do.
Since we already called
tf.summary.merge_all on the next
line, any new summary metrics
we add to our graph will
automatically get picked up
and added to our log files.
Let's run the code to train
our network and generate
log files that we can view in TensorBoard.
But first, if you already have
a log subfolder in PyCharm,
delete that before continuing.
Right click, Delete.
Okay let's run the code,
right click and Run.
Okay the logs were created,
now we're ready to open up
TensorBoard, open up a
terminal window in PyCharm,
I like the bottom left,
terminal, and we'll type
tensorboard--logdire equals
and in this case 05/logs.
Note that on Windows you'll
use a backslash instead of
a forward slash and then press Enter.
When TensorBoard it will give
you a URL to open in your
browser, copy and paste
that to your browser.
And now let's go to the
web browser and paste.
At the top of TensorBoard
click Histograms to see our new
histogram.
And then expand the logging subsection.
Now to look at one of these
charts in more detail let's
click the Expand button.
This chart shows us the range
of predictions our neural
network made each step during training.
Back here at step zero,
we can see the predictions
made were very low and
all grouped together.
But as we move forward in
time, we can see that the learn
to make predictions with
a wider range of values.
Because our data was scaled
to the zero to one range,
we'd expect the predictions
right out of the neural network
to roughly cover that
same zero to one range.
TensorBoard also lets us
visualize histograms as
a distribution chart.
Click on Distributions at the top.
And expand logging and
let's expand this chart.
These graphs show the same
data as a 2D chart over time.
We can see at the beginning of training,
all the predictions were small
and grouped tightly together.
Then over time it learned
to make a wider range
of predictions, when you're
building your own machine
learning models, it's a great
idea to add visualizations
of any inputs and outputs
you want to model.
Doing that will make it a
lot easier to understand what
your model is actually doing.
When you're done with
TensorBoard, you can close it
by going back to the terminal
window and hitting Control C.