- If you are new to machine learning,
you may be wondering what
TensorFlow actually is.
TensorFlow is a software
framework for building
and deploying machine learning models.
Machine learning is a different approach
than traditional programming.
With traditional programming,
we write the program
that tells the computer
exactly what to do to complete the task.
With machine learning, we don't explicitly
tell the computer how to do something.
Instead we show a training data
and the machine learning
algorithm uses the training data
that come up with its own
rules to complete the task.
Developed at Google,
TensorFlow was designed
to be a common platform for
building machine learning
applications internally.
In late 2015, they decided
to share it with the world
and release it as an
open source application.
TensorFlow is licensed
under the Apache open source
software license.
That means you can use it,
modify it, and even redistribute
modified version of it.
You don't have to pay any
licensing fees to use TensorFlow.
TensorFlow gives you the
basic building blocks
that you need to design, train,
and deploy machine learning models.
While it's flexible enough
to be used for several
different types of machine
learning types of algorithms,
it's typically used to
build deep neural networks.
Deep neural networks built with TensorFlow
are used in many different areas like
image recognition, where you recognize
what objects appear in a picture.
Speech recognition
where you turn speech into text.
Image style transfer
where you can make a photograph
look like it was painted
in the style of a famous artist,
or language translation
where you translate
from one human language
to another.
In this particular course,
we'll use TensorFlow to solve
a typical business problem
estimating sales.
We'll build a basic neural network
that can estimate the
sales of a new video game
based on sales of past video games
with similar characteristics.
But everything we learn
about building and deploying
with TensorFlow works the
same way no matter what kind
of application you are using it for.
TensorFlow isn't the only
option for deep learning.
TensorFlow is comparable to
other deep learning frameworks like
Theano, Torch, and Pytorch.
Each framework has its own pros and cons,
but all of them are popular
within different research groups
and companies.
It's common for a machine
learning researcher
to be familiar with several of them.
Since TensorFlow was Google solution,
Google has helped promote
it, and its become
one of the more popular choices.
It also works well with
many Google products
like their Cloud ML platform
and for deploying machine learning models
and Android mobile phones.
TensorFlow is a low level toolkit.
It can take quite a few lines of code
to build a machine learning
model in TensorFlow.
Because of this, there are
wrappers for TensorFlow
that simplify common operations.
The most popular wrapper
for TensorFlow is Keras.
Keras is a high level programming toolkit
that makes it easy to
build many different types
of neural networks with
only a few lines of code.
Keras still uses TensorFlow
behind the scenes
to actually do the processing.
It's a great choice if you
don't need the low level
flexibility of TensorFlow.
My recommendation is to
learn how to use TensorFlow
on its own first, to
make sure you understand
what's going on behind the scenes.
But once you're familiar with TensorFlow,
it's great to also learn how to use Keras.
It makes many common tasks much easier
and it can be a great time saver.