- [Teacher] Alright, what's with the name?
The name TensorFlow comes
from the design of the system.
TensorFlow is designed to
work with large data sets
made up of many different
individual attributes.
Any data that you want to
process with TensorFlow
has to be stored in the
multi-dimensional array.
These multi-dimensional arrays
are also called tensors.
To run operations on the data set,
you construct a computational graph
similar to a flow chart
that determines how data flows
from one operation to the next.
So it's called TensorFlow
because you're defining
how data or tensors
will flow through the system.
Here, we are passing in two
tensors, adding those numbers,
squaring them and then
outputting the result
as another tensor.
TensorFlow is designed to be
very generic and open-ended.
You can define the graph of operations
that does any calculation that you want.
While TensorFlow is most often used
to build deep neural networks,
it can be used to build nearly anything
that involves processing data
by running a series of
mathematical operations.
There are pros and cons
to this open-ended design.
This design makes TensorFlow
very powerful and flexible.
It can be adapted to do almost anything,
but on the other hand,
this make TensorFlow difficult
for new users to learn
since very little is done for you.
In this course,
we'll focus on the most common
operations you'll need to use
to build and deploy neural
networks with TensorFlow.