- [Instructor] Let's talk about
the tangibles you need to get started.
TensorFlow has different hardware
and software requirements
for the development phase
and the runtime phase.
The Development phase is
when you are first coding
and then training a neural network.
This is usually done on your own computer.
The Runtime phase, also
called the inference phase,
is when you are using a
trained neural network
to make predictions.
This might be done on your own
computer, on a cloud server,
or on a user's computer, or mobile device.
When you are developing
machine learning models with TensorFlow,
you need a computer running
Windows, macOS, or Linux.
For very large projects
you might take advantage
of multiple Linux computers in the cloud
to speed up processing.
But once you have a trained model
you can run it on a wider range
of computers and hardware devices.
You can run your trained models
on Mac, Windows, and Linux desktops,
as a web service on Linux servers
using the TensorFlow Serving application,
in the cloud with
Google's Cloud ML service,
and on iOS or Android mobile devices.
The flexibility to run the
same machine learning model
on many different platforms
is one of the best features of TensorFlow.
TensorFlow can take
advantage of video cards
with GPUs, or graphics processing units,
to speed up training.
GPUs are chips originally designed
to speed up 3D video games
but they are also good at
the algebraic calculations
needed to train neural networks.
In fact deep learning is only possible
because GPUs let us train
large neural networks
in a reasonable amount of time.
Keep in mind that TensorFlow
only supports NVIDIA-brand GPUs.
Video cards with GPUs produced
by other vendors won't
work with TensorFlow.
You won't need a video card
with a GPU to complete this class.
But having one is helpful when
working on large projects.
Using a GPU can reduce the time needed
to train a large neural
network from days to minutes.
Using a GPU with TensorFlow
requires installing
additional software libraries
from NVIDIA that aren't open source.
Just installing TensorFlow
on its own won't be enough
to take advantage of a GPU.
TensorFlow's core execution engine
is written in C++ for speed.
But C++ can be a cumbersome
language to work with.
To make things easier TensorFlow
lets other programming
languages control the C++ core.
The best supported language
for TensorFlow development is Python.
Python is a high level
programming language
that is easy to learn
and quick to develop in.
The main downside of using Python
is that it is relatively slow to execute
compared to a low level
language like C or C++.
But TensorFlow works around this problem.
Your Python code defines the structure
of your machine learning model
but TensorFlow's high
performance execution engine
actually pushes data through the model
and performs all the mathematical
operations using C++.
Since all the heavy lifting happens inside
the high performance execution engine
you still get great performance.