- [Instructor] In this course,
we'll be using TensorFlow
to build and deploy
a supervised machine learning model.
Supervised machine learning is the branch
of machine learning where we train
the model by showing it input data
and the expected result for that data.
And it works out how
to transform the input
into the output.
When building and using a supervised
machine learning model,
there's a process we always follow
called the model of train,
test, evaluation flow.
First, we'll need to choose which
machine learning algorithm we want to use
to build our model.
We can pick any standard
machine learning algorithm
but in this course we'll
be using neural networks.
Then we can start with the train phase.
We train the algorithm by
showing it training data
and the expected output for that data
and it has to figure out how to come up
with the expected result.
In other words,
the algorithm learns how
to transform the input
to produce the correct output.
For example, we can train
it to do multiplication
by showing it two numbers
and the expected result
and it will eventually work out
that we want to multiply the two numbers.
After we train the model,
we'll load up a second set of data
it has never seen before
called the testing data set.
This is the test phase.
We'll feed this testing
data through the model
and make sure it is able to
predict the correct result
even though it has never
seen this data before.
This shows that the model actually learned
how to solve the problem
in the general way
and didn't just memorize the answers
for the training data.
Finally, once the model
is trained and tested,
we can use it.
This is the evaluation phase.
We'll pass in new data and it will tell us
the answer it calculated.
In TensorFlow, we'll
follow these same steps
when building a model.
But with TensorFlow,
we have to set up a lot of the mechanics
of this ourselves.
First we code our machine
learning algorithm.
We'll do that by building
a computational graph
of operations that TensorFlow can run.
Here's how we'll implement
a neural network.
First we'll define each
layer of the neural network
and connect them together
so that data flows
from the first layer
through to the last layer.
Then we'll add the placeholder node
that represents the data that will be fed
in as input to the neural network.
And another placeholder node
that represents the output,
or values predicted by the neural network.
Next, we need a way to
measure the accuracy
of the neural network's predictions.
We'll define the function
that measures the accuracy
of each prediction during
the training process.
This is called a loss function.
The loss function gets added to the graph
as its own operation.
Then we have to create
an optimizer function
that tells TensorFlow how
we want to train the model.
When we run this function,
it will perform one
training step on our model.
TensorFlow provides many
pre-built optimizer functions
so usually we just have to
tell it which one to use
and we don't need to
implement custom code.
We'll call this node
the training operation.
The training operation will
train the neural network
by looking at the results
of the loss function
and using that to adjust
the weights of each layer
in the neural network until
they produce the desired output.
Because this is a computational graph,
there's no single start or end.
We can start processing
at any node in the graph.
For example,
if we want to run one step of training,
we can run the training operation.
And if we want to make a
prediction for new data,
we can run the output operation.
When you run an operation,
TensorFlow will push any needed data
through the network
according to the pathways
you defined to make everything work.
Now that the machine learning algorithm
is fully defined as a computational graph,
we can move on to the training phase.
But before we can execute
any of the operations
in our graph,
we have to create a Tensorflow session.
A session is an object intenser flow
that runs operations on the graph
and tracks the state of
each node in the graph.
Once the session object is created,
we can ask it to run any
operation in the graph.
To train the model,
we'll call the training
operation over and over.
Each time the training operation runs,
we'll pass a new training data
that will be used for that training pass.
And then we'll check the current accuracy
by calling the loss function.
While the training process is running,
we can watch the results graphically
using a separate tool called TensorBoard.
TensorBoard is a web based application
that lets us visually monitor
the system in real time.
We can use the graphs in TensorBoard
to monitor how the accuracy is improving
as the training process continues to run.
Now that the model is trained,
we can move on to the testing phase.
We pass in test data,
and then measure the accuracy
by calling the loss function.
The data will flow
through the neural network
and into the loss function.
The loss function will tell us how
close the values predicted by
the neural network were
to the real testing data.
Once we are happy with the
accuracy of the predictions,
we can save this model to a file.
When we save a trained model,
we're actually writing
out a copy of this graph,
and the state of all nodes in the graph.
When we load the model later,
we're just restoring the
graph to it's previous state.
Now that we have a trained model,
we'll load it up to restore the graph.
To use the model to make new predictions,
we'll feed in data to the input node
and call the output operation.
The data will flow
through the neural network
to the output node.
As you can see,
the different nodes of
the computational graph
are used for different phases
of the train test evaluation flow.
In fact, when we are in
the evaluation phase,
and only using the graph
to make new predictions,
the loss function and
the training operation
are no longer needed at all.
To make new predictions,
all we need are the nodes that make
up the neural network itself.
So when we deploy a trained neural network
to the cloud or to a mobile device,
we can strip out all the other parts
of the computational graph
and only include the parts
we need to make predictions.