- [Voiceover] Let's
practice the basic mechanics
of TensorFlow by starting
with something simple.
Let's build a TensorFlow
computational graph
that adds two numbers together.
Here's what the computational
graph will look like.
This graph has two inputs, X and Y.
Those are the two numbers
we want to add together.
This graph also has one
operation called 'addition'.
That note simply adds together
the tensors passed into it.
Once this graph is defined, we can use it
by creating a new TensorFlow session.
Then we'll feed in values for X and Y,
and we'll ask the session object
to execute the addition node.
The result we get back from executing
the addition node will be the answer.
Let's open up addition.py.
Here on line two, we've
imported TensorFlow
so we have access to it.
It's standard practice to
import it with the name 'TF'
so that we don't have to type out
the whole word 'TensorFlow' every time
we want to call a function.
Next on line five, notice that I've called
OS.Environ to set this
environment variable to two.
This just tells TensorFlow
not to output as many
log messages as it normally does.
By default, TensorFlow
outputs a lot of log messages
to your console when you run the program.
The messages can sometimes be helpful,
but I've turned them off for these demos
to make the output easier to read.
Feel free to remove this
line from any of the examples
if you want to see the full
TensorFlow logging output.
Next, let's define the
X and Y input nodes.
When you create a node in
TensorFlow, you have to choose
what kind of node to create.
The X and Y nodes will
be placeholder nodes
that get assigned a new value
every time we make a calculation,
so we'll create them as
a TF.placeholder node
and I'll create the
first node on line eight.
TF.placeholder...
When we create a placeholder node,
we have to pass on the data type.
We'll be adding numbers
here, so we can use
a floating point data-type.
I'll use TF.float32.
We also need to give this node the name.
The name will show up when we look
at graphical visualizations of our model.
I'll name this node X by passing
in the parameter called
'name' with a value of X,
and now let's define Y the same way.
TF.placeholder, pass in
the data-type, TF.float32
and give the name, Name Y.
Now we can define the node that
does the addition operation.
In TensorFlow we can do that
by creating a TF.Add node,
let's do that on line eleven.
TF.add
Then we'll pass on the X and Y nodes
to the addition node,
that tells TensorFlow
to link those nodes on
the computational graph,
so we're asking it to pull
the values from X and Y
and add the result.
Let's also give the
addition node the name.
Name equals addition.
And that's the entire definition
for our simple computational graph.
The model only has three nodes,
so we can define it with
just three lines of code
but when you're building
more complex models,
this code can get quite complicated.
To execute operations in the graph,
we have to create a session.
We create a session
object this way on line 15
with TF.session as session.
Now that we have a session,
we can ask the session
to run operations on
their computational graph
by calling Session.run.
On line 17, we'll say
result equals session.run,
then we need to pass on the
operation we want to run,
in this case addition.
When the addition operation runs,
it's going to see that it
needs to grab the values
of the X and Y nodes, so we also need
to feed in values for X and Y.
We can do that by supplying a
parameter called 'feed dict'
so on line 17 I'll add
a feed dict parameter
and then we'll pass in X and give them
the ray value of one, and Y,
and pass in a value of four as a ray.
And then finally in line 19,
we'll just print the result.
Let's run this code, I'm going
to right-click and choose 'run'
we're choosing run from the context menu
because the keyboard
shortcuts are different
on each operating system, but feel free
to learn and use the keyboard
shortcut if you'd like.
Okay, click 'run', and
the result is down here
in the console, we can see
we got the right answer,
which is five.
Notice that I passed
in the rays on line 17
for the values of X and Y, and the result
we got back from TensorFlow
is also in the ray.
That's because TensorFlow
always works with tensors,
which are multi-dimensional rays.
It's expecting us to feed in the rays
and it will return rays, that means
we can feed in multiple numbers at once
for X and Y, let's feed in
some more numbers on line 17.
For X we're going to
feed in one, two, ten,
and for Y we're going to
feed in four, two, ten.
And let's run the code
again by right-click 'run'.
Now in the console we can see
that we got back three separate
sums, five, four and twenty.
We could even pass in
multi-dimensional rays
for X and Y and it would
still work the same way
because we aren't just
adding together two numbers,
we're actually adding
together two tensors.
This might seem like a lot of work
to add some numbers together,
just to do addition,
we had to define the
model, create a session,
pass in data, and then send it off
to the TensorFlow execution
engine and wait for the result.
But TensorFlow's real value
is when we are working
with large data sets
and computationally intensive operations.
It can take the same operational graph
we've defined here, and execute
it across multiple machines
who are using graphics cards with GPUs
to accelerate processing.
The same code in TensorFlow can scale
from running on a low power
device like a cell phone,
all the way up to running
on multiple servers
in a massive data center.