- To work with the code
examples in this course,
we need to install the Python
3 programming language,
the PyCharm development environment,
and several software libraries,
including TensorFlow.
This video will cover
installation on Mac OS.
If you are using Windows,
watch the separate video
covering Windows installation instead.
The method we'll use to install TensorFlow
will only install the
core TensorFlow libraries.
It won't install the
additional components needed
to take advantage of the video card's GPU
to accelerate processing.
Using a GPU requires special hardware
that won't be needed for this course,
but if you would like
to install TensorFlow
with GPU support, please refer
to the more detailed
installation instructions
on the TensorFlow website
for the additional steps
you need to follow.
Okay, let's get to it.
First, let's install Python 3.
We're at the python.org website.
At the top of the page,
click on Downloads.
Now, we'll see the newest version
of Python 3 available for Mac OS.
Click to download Python 3.
Click on the downloaded file
to launch the installer.
We can accept all the default options.
Mac OS actually comes with
Python 2 already installed,
but Python 3 is the
current version of Python,
and it has several nice improvements,
like improved support for working
with text in different languages.
Either version can be
used for machine learning,
but there's no reason not
to use the latest version.
Great, the installation is complete.
Next, we need to install PyCharm.
PyCharm is an integrated
development environment for Python.
Let's go to jetbrains.com/pycharm.
Okay, click Download Now,
and we'll choose the Mac version
which is already selected.
We now have the choice of
downloading the community edition
or the professional edition.
Either will work, but the
community edition is free
and has all the features we need.
So let's download the community edition.
When the download completes,
click on the file to open it.
To install it, just drag the application
to the applications folder.
Now, let's run PyCharm from
the applications folder,
and click Open.
The first time we launch PyCharm,
it will ask us some questions.
We can just accept the
defaults and move forward.
Now we are ready to create a new project.
Click Create New Project.
When you create the
project, choose the folder
where you have downloaded
the exercise files,
if you have them available.
For the interpreter, choose
the version of Python 3
that you've just installed.
It will probably be selected by default,
and click Create.
It will pop up a dialogue that tells us
that the files already exist.
Just click Yes,
and you can close the tool tip window.
Now, let's open one of the exercise files.
I'll click on 02, and
click on Edition Final.
As soon as we try to open the file,
PyCharm will tell us
that some package requirements
are missing at the top.
Click Install Requirements,
and then click Install to confirm.
Depending on the version
of Mac OS you are using,
this process may take quite a bit of time.
If there's no pre-compiled version
of scikit-learn available for your OS,
you'll have to recompile from scratch,
but just let it run until it's done.
You can monitor the progress
in the bar at the bottom.
Great, we are ready to get started.