- To work with the code
examples in this course,
we need to install the Python
3 programming language,
the PyCharm development environment,
and several software libraries
including TensorFlow.
This video will cover
installation on Windows.
If you're using Mac OS, watch the separate
video covering Mac installation instead.
The method we'll use to install
TensorFlow in this video
will only install the
core TensorFlow libraries.
It won't install the
additional components needed
to take advantage of a video card's
GPU to accelerate processing.
Using a GPU requires special hardware
and won't be needed for this course,
but if you would like to
install TensorFlow with
GPU support, please refer to
the more detailed instructions
on the TensorFlow website
for the additional steps
you'll need to follow.
First, let's install Python 3.
On Windows, we'll be using the Anaconda
distribution of Python.
Many Python machine learning libraries
were first developed for Linux,
and they can be difficult to
install correctly on Windows.
Anaconda provides pre-packaged versions of
Python machine learning libraries,
which makes installation
on Windows a lot easier.
We're at the continuum.io website.
Click download Anaconda.
Since we're using Windows,
we'll choose to download
the Windows version.
Click.
Now we have the choice
between Python 3 and Python 2.
Click to download Python 3.
Now that the download is finished,
let's launch the installer.
Click run.
We can accept all the default options.
Next.
And install.
When we downloaded Anaconda,
we had the choice between
Python 2 and Python 3.
Python 3 is the newer version of Python
that has several nice improvements,
like better support for working
with texts in other languages.
So that's what we'll use for this course,
and what I'd recommend you
use for your own projects,
but sometimes you might see code online
written for Python 2 that hasn't
been updated for Python 3.
In that case, you can install
Python 2 using the same process.
You can have both versions
installed at the same time.
Great, the installation is complete.
Click Next,
and uncheck,
and Finish.
Now we need to install PyCharm.
PyCharm is an integrated
development environment for Python.
Go to jetbrains.com/PyCharm.
Okay, click Download Now,
and then make sure you've
chosen the Windows version.
We have the choice of
downloading the community edition
or the professional edition.
Either will work, but the
community edition is free
and has all the features we need,
so let's download the community edition.
Click.
Alright, click and launch the installer.
Click Run.
We can accept all the defaults.
Click Next,
and Next,
and Install.
Great, it's done.
Let's click to run PyCharm, and Finish.
The first time we launch PyCharm,
it'll ask us some questions.
We can just accept the defaults,
and click Accept,
and OK.
Now we are ready to create a project.
Click Create New Project.
When we create the project,
choose the folder where you've
downloaded the exercise files
if you have them available.
Okay.
Next we need to configure
the Python interpreter.
By default, Anaconda has
installed 3.6 for us here.
But currently, TensorFlow
on Windows only works
with Python 3.5, so we need
to install that as well.
Click on the gear icon,
and click Create Conda Environment.
For the name, let's call it TensorFlow.
For the Python version,
make sure you've chosen 3.5,
and then click OK.
Now PyCharm will configure
Python 3.5 for us.
Okay, now click Create.
And then click Yes to confirm.
And close.
Before we continue, we need
to take a little detour
to manually install TensorFlow.
Because of the way it's
distributed for Windows,
we need to install it
from the command line.
To do that, let's open up the search bar
and run the Anaconda Prompt application.
Now we are at a Command Prompt.
The first step is to activate
the Python 3.5 environment
that we just created so that TensorFlow
gets installed into the correct place.
To do that, type "activate
TensorFlow" and hit enter.
Now we're ready to install TensorFlow.
The easiest way to do this is to
cut and paste the command
from the TensorFlow website.
Let's go back to the TensorFlow website,
click on Install,
and then we're going to click
Installing TensorFlow on Windows,
and then we're going to scroll down until
we get to the section that
says Installing with Anaconda,
and then finally we're going to
copy the command from number 4,
under installing the CPU-only
version of TensorFlow.
So I'm going to cut and paste this command
into the Command Prompt application.
Control + C,
and then now I'm going to
tap the Command Prompt,
and then right click
to paste and hit Enter.
Great, when it says everything
was successfully isntalled,
you can close the Command Prompt window.
Now let's switch back to PyCharm.
Let's open up one of the
source files in PyCharm.
Click on Exercise Files,
and 02, and addition final.py.
As soon as we open the
file, PyCharm will tell us
that some of the package
requirements are still missing.
These are the other
machine learning libraries
we'll be using in the course.
Click Install requirements,
and then click Install.
You might receive this
error that says the package
google-api-python-client is not satisfied.
That's okay, we can work around this.
First, let's use the search bar
to open up the Anaconda prompt again.
Next, let's type "activate TensorFlow,"
and hit Enter.
Then we can manually install
the package with this command,
"conda install -c conda-forge,"
and then the name of the package,
which is google-api-python-client.
Then hit Enter.
Then hit Enter to proceed.
Great, now everything is ready to go.